# PHILLIP PHAN

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER



#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML, CSS
JAVASCRIPT, REACT
RUBY
PYTHON, DJANGO
GIT AND GITHUB
OBJECT-ORIENTED PROGRAMMING

# PERSONAL PROJECTS

### SketchBook:

SketchBook is an app that gives users a creative outlet by allowing users to design and edit drawings made on the app. The "SketchPad" page presents users with an input to choose the size of the sketch. Once the SketchPad is generated, users are able to design their sketch by drawing, erasing, and choosing various colors. Users are also able to save the sketch to their "SketchBook". On the "SketchBook" page, users are able to view all of their drawings as well as edit them individually. SketchBook is a fun alternative to pen and paper for the average doodler.

- Full CRUD functionality using React hooks to manage state
- JSON server used as a local database
- React Bootstrap used to style CSS

GitHub Repo:

https://github.com/phillipphan/sketchbook

#### **GROUP PROJECTS**

## Nutshell:

Nutshell is a social media application built by a team of three developers where users are able to create events, tasks, and messages that are only viewable by those who have followed each other.

- Single-page application built with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Full CRUD functionality for "Friends", "Tasks", and "Events"
- JSON server used as a local database

GitHub Repo:

https://github.com/phillipphan/reactivenutshell-garment-of-illusions-1

## **ABOUT ME**

My passion lies in creating solutions based on personal and business needs through data analysis, developmental research, and a constant strive to learn more. I enjoy the challenges of developing real-world applications from novel ideas. My colleagues would describe me as a driven and resourceful individual with a positive, proactive attitude when faced with adversity. I have strong technical skills and an academic background in software development as well as in Biochemistry and Cellular and Molecular Biology.

#### TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

#### **NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL**

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER | JAN 2021 - JUNE 2021

Intensive six-month full stack software development program creating web applications in team-based environments, as well as individually.

- Developed dynamic single-page applications using React as well as vanilla JavaScript
- Git and GitHub for version control
- Database planning by creating entity relationship diagrams to define relationships between data resources

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### ASSURED BIO LABS

Lab Intern | MAY 2020 - AUG 2020

Responsible for improving efficiency in workflow for genetic extractions, sample preparation, and microbial culturing. Built technical skills in lab environments and learned about the business model of industrial sciences.

- Helped optimize current standard operating procedures by pinpointing and reducing idle times without affecting end results.
- Participated in research and development projects through proposing and implementing solutions to issues that arise during testing.
- Collaborated with the Marketing Coordinator to increase client interactions and retention.

#### **OMBRE NAILS**

Front-Desk Receptionist | MAY 2016 - May 2020

Responsible for managing the workflow of a business of 10 employees and its clients by assigning clients and duties to each technician throughout the day. Supported technicians by meeting client demands while service is being provided. Built managerial and client interaction experience.

• Presented original solutions to help manage and record the workflow throughout the day.

# **EDUCATION**

**B.S. IN BIOCHEMISTRY AND CELLULAR AND MOLECULAR BIOLOGY** 

University of Tennessee | 2016 - 2020

GPA: 3.81 Summa Cum Laude